# **Daehwa Kim**

407 South Craig Street, Pittsburgh, PA 15213 daehwak@cs.cmu.edu • +1 415 937 4111 • https://daehwa.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My recent research explores the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction, Sensing, and Machine Learning, particularly on transforming antenna systems into advanced interface technologies. I enhance wireless sensing capabilities to improve machine perception, focusing on tracking of the human body, hand, and mouth poses as new input paradigms of spatial computing and facilitating dexterous manipulations. I interned at Apple AIML (2024) and Meta Reality Labs (2023). I presented papers at prestigious computer science conferences such as ACM CHI, UIST, UbiComp, and have received two Best Paper Honorable Mention awards at CHI.

#### **EDUCATION**

Mention awards at CHI.

Ph.D. student, Carnegie Mellon University, School of Computer Science,

Sep 2022 – Current

Advised by Prof. Chris Harrison at Future Interfaces Group

# M.Sc., KAIST, School of Computing

**Human-Computer Interaction Institute** 

Mar 2019 – Feb 2021

- Advised by Prof. Geehyuk Lee at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
- Graduated with 2020 Best Thesis Award

### B.S., UNIST, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

- Computer Science and Engineering (Major) and Electrical Engineering (Minor)
- Entered with top honors.
- Summer session program, University of the Arts London, London, UK

Jul 2018

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Apple AIML, Cupertino, CA

May 2024 – Aug 2024

- ML Research Intern
- Manager: Mario Srouji

### Meta Reality Labs, Redmond, WA

May 2023 – Aug 2023

- Research Scientist Intern
- Manager: Eric Whitmire

#### Future Interfaces Group, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Sep 2021 – Apr 2022

- Research Associate, Human-Computer Interaction Institute
- Advisor: Chris Harrison

# AWARDS & HONORS

Best Paper Honorable Mention Award (Top 5%) ACM CHI	May 2022
Best Paper Honorable Mention Award (Top 5%), ACM CHI	May 2021
Best Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing	Feb 2021
Dean's List for five semesters, UNIST	Mar 2015 – Feb 2019
<b>Uni-Star Scholarship</b> for top ranking in entrance exam, UNIST	Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] Andy Kong, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Chris Harrison, "Power-over-Skin: On-Body Devices Powered Using Intra-Body RF Energy" in *Proceedings of the 37th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Pittsburgh, PA, USA, Oct 2024. (Conditionally accepted)
- [2] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Eric Whitmire, Roger Boldu, Wolf Kienzle, and Hrvoje Benko, "SoundScroll: Robust Finger Slide Detection Using Friction Sound and Wrist-Worn Microphones" in *Proceedings of the 2024 ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computers*, Melbourne, VIC, Australia, Oct 2024. (Accepted with minor revision)
- [3] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Vimal Mollyn, and Chris Harrison, "WorldPoint: Finger Pointing as a Rapid and Natural Trigger for In-The-Wild Mobile Interactions" in *Proceedings of the 2023 ACM International Conference on Interactive Surfaces and Spaces*, Pittsburgh, USA, Nov 2023.
- [4] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, and Chris Harrison, "Pantœnna: Mouth Pose Estimation for VR/AR Headsets Using Low-Profile Antenna and Impedance Characteristic Sensing" in *Proceedings of the 36th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, San Francisco, USA, Oct 2023.

- [5] Hui-Shyong Yeo, Erwin Wu, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Juyoung Lee, Hyung-il Kim, Seo Young Oh, Luna Takagi, Woontack Woo, Hideki Koike, and Aaron J Quigley, "OmniSense: Exploring Novel Input Sensing and Interaction Techniques on Mobile Device with Omni-Directional Camera" in *Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Hamburg, Germany, Apr 2023.
- [6] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, and Chris Harrison, "EtherPose: Continuous Hand Pose Tracking with Wrist-Worn Antenna Impedance" in *Proceedings of the 35th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Bend, Oregon, USA, Oct 2022.
- **Q**[7] Craig Shultz, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Karan Ahuja, and Chris Harrison, "TriboTouch: Micro-Patterned Surfaces for Low Latency Touchscreens" in *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, New Orleans, LA, USA, Apr 2022. **Best Paper Honorable Mention Award; Top 5**%
- Q[8] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. Best Paper Honorable Mention Award; Top 5%
  - [9] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of* the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020.
- [10] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020.

#### **PATENTS**

- [1] Istvan J. Szini, Chris Harrison, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, "Continuous hand pose tracking with wrist-worn antenna impedance characteristic sensing" US20240103605A1, Apple Inc, Mar 2024.
- [2] Geehyuk Lee, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, "Electronic device for supporting finger pinch interaction using return loss of radio frequency signal and operating method thereof" US20220244787A1, Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, Aug 2022.
- [3] Seungin Park, Hyongeuk Lee, Sunggeun Ahn, Geehyuk Lee, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, "Method and apparatus for predicting object of interest of user" US11361540B2, Samsung Electronics Co Ltd, KAIST, Sep 2021.

# ACADEMIC SERVICE

#### Reviewer

UIST '24, SIGGRAPH '24 Poster, CHI '24, IMWUT '23, SIGGRAPH '23 Poster, UIST '23, CHI '23, UIST '22, CHI '22 LBW, IMWUT '21, CHI '21 LBW